{"tossups": [{"question": "During this event, William the Pig and Hugh the Iron o\u21b5ered free transport, but took their unwitting passengers to Tunisia. A leader of this event is apocryphally said to have performed miracles at the Cathedral Saint-Denis [sahn deh-NEE]. One leader of this campaign, Stephen of Cloyes [kloy], said he had a letter from Jesus to the King of France. Nicholas of Cologne\u2019s prediction that the sea by Genoa would part for this campaign obviously did not come true, and when this crusade ended, most of its participants were sold into slavery. For the point, name this 1212 crusade named for its youthful participants.", "answer": "<b> Children\u2019s Crusade</b> (\u201dcrusade\u201d not needed after mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "During this event, thousands of prisoners were held at the ESMA, a former school for naval mechanics. The Mothers of the Plaza de Mayo hold annual protests over people who disappeared in this event, many of whom were dropped into the Atlantic Ocean during Death Flights. This event began after the kidnapping of students in the Night of the Pencils, marking the start of the National Reorganization Process. Jorge Videla\u2019s government instigated, for the point, what period of violence against perceived leftist insurgents in Argentina?", "answer": "<b> Dirty War</b> (accept<b> National Reorganization Process</b> before mentioned; prompt on Operation Condor)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This work\u2019s argument may have been inspired by a meeting with Carl Melchior. This work ominously ended by warning that men listen to whatever \u201chope, illusion, or revenge\u201d is given to them during\u201ceconomic privation.\u201d This book, whose ideas were roughly implemented much later by the Marshall Plan, attacked a so-called \u201cCarthaginian peace\u201d and foresaw the devastating inflation that reparations would create. For the point, name this 1919 work that criticized the strict conditions imposed on Germany by the Treaty of Versailles, written by John Maynard Keynes.", "answer": "The<b> Economic Consequences of the Peace</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Other Social Science"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "According to legend, this man\u2019s advisor realized he made a mistake in tactics after hearing a woman scolding her son for eating hot gruel. The satraps Nicanor and Philip may have been killed by this man\u2019s forces. A thousand mile road built during this man\u2019s rule from Pataliputra to Bihar was recorded in history by Megasthenes. This man, who was succeeded by Bindusara, overthrew the Nanda Dynasty. For the point, name this grandfather of Ashoka and founder of the Mauryan Dynasty.", "answer": "<b> Chandragupta</b> Maurya", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "An \u201cofficial peace version\u201d of this song from 1919 rewrites its warlike second stanza. Muzio Clementi paid tribute to his adopted land by quoting this song in his<em> Great National Symphony</em>, and early versions of this song included a verse celebrating Field Marshal Wade in opposition to the Jacobites. John Bull is sometimes cited as the composer of this song\u2019s melody, which is also used for the national anthem of Liechtenstein and the American song \u201cMy Country, Tis of Thee.\u201d For the point, name this national anthem of the United Kingdom.", "answer": "<b> God Save The Queen</b> (or<b> God Save The King</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This group\u2019s predecessors included the ROPCIO and KOR, and its actions led to the amending of its nation\u2019s constitution in the April Novelization. This group chose strategically significant dates, such as the signing of the July Manifesto and its country\u2019s 1791 constitution, for its protests and strikes. This organization engaged the government of Wojciech Jaruzelski [voy-check yaru-zel-skee] in the Round Table Talks, securing free elections in 1989. For the point, name this group that was founded at the Lenin Shipyards in Gdansk, a Polish trade union once led by Lech Walesa [lek vah-wen-sah].", "answer": "Independent Self-Governing Labor Union<b> Solidarity</b> (accept<b> Solidarno\u00b4s\u00b4c</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Elizabeth Harris was one of the first preachers of this religious group in America. Diary-writer John Woolman convinced many members of this religious group to free their slaves. Mary Dyer was one of three people from this group executed in Massachusetts called the Boston Martyrs. A leader of this group signed a treaty with the Lenape under a white oak tree, established a colony dubbed the \u201cHoly Experiment,\u201dand founded the city of Philadelphia. For the point, name this religious group once led by William Penn that is also known as the Society of Friends.", "answer": "<b> Quaker</b>s (accept Society of<b> Friend</b>s before read)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This leader had his Chief Justice, Benedicto Kiwanuka, murdered shortly after taking power. As a general, this man forced his country\u2019s Kabaka people into exile at the Battle of Mengo Hill. This leader took power in a coup while his predecessor was attending a Commonwealth Conference in Singapore. This leader was ousted after he launched a failed invasion of the Kagera region of his southern neighbor, and he infamously gave his country\u2019s Asian population 90 days to leave the country. For the point, name this Ugandan dictator for most of the 1970s.", "answer": "Idi<b> Amin</b> Dada", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "For the point, name these photovoltaic devices that convert sunlight into electricity.", "answer": "<b> solar cell</b> (accept<b> photovoltaic cell</b> before mentioned; accept<b> solar panel</b>s and other equivalents)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "In an address to the Senate, this man claimed that the gravest question, \u201cHow can the Union be preserved?\u201d, could only be answered by the North, not the South. This man claimed that every civilization was founded upon a system of two classes in a speech that labeled slavery as \u201ca positive good.\u201d James Murray Mason delivered this man\u2019s speech in opposition to the Compromise of 1850 on March 4 in the month of his death. For the point, name this South Carolina senator and states\u2019 rights advocate, a member of the Great Triumvirate.", "answer": "John C.<b> Calhoun</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "For the point, name this country whose<em> Regia Marina</em> was led by Admiral Angelo Iachino.", "answer": "<b> Italy</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This mountain was first scaled by botanist Edwin James. Nikola Tesla built his first functional coil while working on this mountain. The namesake of this mountain was killed while commanding troops at the Battle of York and had previously led a Westward expedition until his capture in Santa Fe. The\u201cFifty-Niners\u201d were a group of gold miners whose slogan was \u201c[this mountain] or bust.\u201d Katharine Bates wrote the song \u201cAmerica the Beautiful\u201d after being inspired by the view from the summit of, for the point, what peak of the Colorado Rockies, named in honor of a 19th-century explorer named Zebulon?", "answer": "<b> Pikes</b> Peak (do not accept or prompt on Pike)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Policeman Greg Kading alleged that this man was killed by a man nicknamed \u201cPoochie.\u201d Shaquille O\u2019Neal has claimed that his presence at an after-party might have prevented this man\u2019s death. The Police\u2019s \u201cEvery Breath You Take\u201d was sampled in \u201cI\u2019ll Be Missing You,\u201d a song written in memory of this man. A man in a blue suit and bowtie opened fire on this man\u2019s Chevrolet Suburban in 1997, just six months after his rival was similarly shot and killed in Las Vegas. For the point, name this rapper behind the album<em> Ready to Die</em>, an East Coast rival of Tupac Shakur.", "answer": "Christopher (George Latore)<b> Wallace</b> (accept the<b> Notorious B.I.G..</b>; accept<b> Biggie Smalls</b>)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "In this country, after the local population resisted the Soviet takeover, Dashnak and Bolshevik forces massacred thousands of people during the March Days. The Musavat Party turned this country into the first Muslim secular democracy before it was overthrown during the Russian Civil War. Soldiers from this country murdered thousands of people of a neighboring ethnicity in the 1920 Shusha Massacre over the status of Nagorno-Karabakh. For the point, name this Caucasian country that fought for three years, and continues to feud, with Armenia.", "answer": "<b> Azerbaijan</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man agreed to limit his own power in the Second Settlement shortly after he was accused of meddling in a trial involving Marcus Primus. The religious altar Ara Pacis was commissioned by this man to serve as a monument to the period of peace he ruled over, the Pax Romana. This man came to power after his admiral Marcus Agrippa was victorious at the Battle of Actium, ending a struggle with Marc Antony. For the point, name this adopted son of Caesar who was crowned Rome\u2019s first emperor.", "answer": "Imperator Caesar Divi Filius<b> Augustus</b> (or<b> Octavian</b>; accept Gaius<b> Octavius</b> Thurinus; accept Gaius Julius Caesar<b> Octavianus</b>; do not prompt on any of the other names alone)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "A literary magazine in this country,<em> Angry Penguins</em>, fell for a hoax involving the fictitious poet Ern Malley; that hoax inspired the 2003 novel<em> My Life as a Fake</em>. Laura Trevelyan is a character in a novel based on the German explorer Ludwig Leichhardt\u2019s death in this country\u2019s desert. For the point, name this country, the setting of many Peter Carey novels and Patrick White\u2019s<em> Voss</em>, which discusses a German explorer who died in its sparse Outback region.", "answer": "<b> Australia</b>", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "The Presidential Unit Citation and two of these decorations were given to Sergeant Reckless, a horse. A civilian award analogous to this medal is the Secretary of Defense Medal for the Defense of Freedom. The Badge of Military Merit was the predecessor of this award, whose medal depicts a gold-colored George Washington in profile. While serving as the officer of a Swift Boat during the Vietnam War, John Kerry received three of, for the point, what military decoration given to soldiers who are wounded or killed in service?", "answer": "<b> Purple Heart</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A physician who worked for this woman wrote<em> Discourse on the Existence of Ghosts</em>, which explained that lack of oxygen could cause failure for corpses to decompose. This woman\u2019s husband lost the Duchy of Lorraine but was given the Grand Duchy of Tuscany instead. Marshal Neipperg lost the Battle of Mollwitz in a war that broke out after this woman gained the throne. In the Treaty of Breslau, this leader ceded much of Silesia to Frederick the Great. For the point, name this queen whose rise to power in 1740 triggered the War of the Austrian Succession.", "answer": "Maria<b> Theresa</b> (Walburga Amalia Christina)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This figure issued the \u201c23 Articles\u201d as a follow-up to his \u201cFormer Ten Points,\u201d which opposed the emphasis on corruption in two other reports. \u201cBombard the Headquarters\u201d was the name of a big-character poster written by this figure during a campaign in which his successor died in a plane crash while fleeing to the Soviet Union. Lin Biao was condemned as a traitor by this man\u2019s government. For the point, name this instigator of the Cultural Revolution and first Communist leader of China.", "answer": "<b> Mao</b> Zedong", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This city\u2019s Academy of Saint Luke hosted lectures by artists who worked in this city like Federico Zuccaro. A scholarship established by Louis XIV called the \u201cPrix [pree] de\u201d [this place] allowed French architects and painters to study in this city. A statue of a personification of this city sits on a pedestal containing reliefs of a wolf and two infants in Jacques-Louis David\u2019s depiction of lictors bringing bodies to Lucius Junius Brutus. The Trevi Fountain is located in, for the point, what Italian city?", "answer": "<b> Rome</b> (or<b> Roma</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This politician proclaimed \u201cI will be your Moses!\u201d while campaigning in his home state. This politician, who attempted to stall the Fenian Raids into Canada, defeated William Brownlow for Congress in 1845 as a defender of the poor. This man\u2019s dislike of Southern planter aristocracy led him to stay loyal to the Union; after the South seceded, this Tennesseean became the only Southern Senator to not resign. For the point, name this National Union Vice President who became President after the assassination of Abraham Lincoln.", "answer": "<b> A</b>ndrew<b> Johnson</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}